# NIKUNJ JADHAV

nixkj3@gmail.com | +91 7977064992 | linktree/Nixk07 | linkedin/nikunj-jadhav

#### **Profile**

A skilled DevOps engineer with **2+ years** of hands-on experience in enterprise-level IT Infrastructure Design, Continuous Integration, and Continuous Deployment (**CI/CD**) on **various cloud providers**.

Skills Certification

Programming Languages: C++, Java, Python, Bash

Databases: MySQL, SQL Services (SSIS, SSRS), phpMyAdmin

Version Control: Git, Github, BitBucket

Web Development: **HTML5**, **CSS3**, **JS**, **PHP**, **Yii2**, **Flask** Python Libraries: **NumPy**, **Pandas**, **Seaborn**, **Matplotlib** 

Cloud Providers: AWS, Azure, GCP

Containerization (**Docker**)
Project management tool: **JIRA** 

Design & Documentation: Canva, Notion

Data Visualization Tableau, Power-BI
Data Analysis with Python | Dphi

Azure Fundamental
Credly Porfolio

PubSub+ Cloud:

Solace Certified Developer practitioner, Solace Certified EDA-practitioner, Solace Certified solutions consultant

## **Work Experience**

DevOps Engineer April 2024 - Current

Solace, Mumbai

- Working as a Junior DevOps Engineer, monitoring daily alerts for Segmentors and Queues using DataDog Monitoring Agent.
- Setting up a **cron script** for **automation** of Daily alerts & monitoring the Uptime of the servers.
- Technologies: Solace, Bash, C, JS, DataDog, etc.

Cloud Associate April 2022 - September 2023

SaphhireInfoTech Ventures, Mumbai

- Worked as a **Cloud Associate**, creating daily reports in **Excel** & handling client mail & processing requests.
- Setting up application servers based on various requirements on the cloud while doing on-prem. to **cloud migration**.
- I also helped create **disaster recovery plans** for various clients, ensuring efficient system operational recovery to their DR site during a catastrophic app failure.
- Technologies: Azure, VM, Storage, S2S, and more; AWS services include EC2, S3, Cloudwatch, VPC, Lambda, IAM, etc.

Software Intern February 2022 - April 2022

Synergy Technology, Mumbai

- Built a CRUD app with Admin Login, phpMyAdmin Database & Flask used with Foreign Key Tables for Music Webpage.
- I built the **plugin** from scratch, adding ease of use for the users. It's integrated into **WordPress**.
- Technologies: HTML, JavaScript, WordPress, PHPMyAdmin, PHP 7, Yii2, Flask.

#### **Web-Development Intern**

Sahu Technologies, Mumbai
 Designed Dynamic UI pages for Hotel management systems and Library Management Systems."

- Created a multi-page interactive website, linked it to a database, and deployed it using "PHPMyAdmin."
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHPMyAdmin.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology (BSc-IT), Mumbai University CGPA: 7.83/10 2019 - 2021

Diploma in Computer Science, Maharashtra State Board of Technical Education (MSBTE) 73% 2016 - 2019

**Projects** 

### Yoga Plus - IIT Bombay's EdTech Hackathon

- Developed an **Android** app & web app in **Flutter** that assists users in performing yoga and workouts by using machine learning models in **TensorFlow Lite**. The user's stats were stored in **Firebase**.
- The web app uses the webcam to capture images and infers poses using the MAX deep learning model
- Technologies: HTML, CSS3, JavaScript, Tensorflow.js, PoseNet, Model Asset Exchange

#### **SOS-Android App**

- Developed an **Android app** that triggers **SOS** via handset buttons without touching the phone screen
- It uses **voice recognition** to send an **SMS** when a certain word is spoken & then sends live location via SMS.
- Technologies: Java, Android Studio, XML, JDBC, and MS-SQL

## **Achievements** Volunteering

Stood 7th in the IIT Bombay EdTech Hackathon Stood 3rd in the Apscript Hackathon Selected in the CII - Debate Competition, State-Level Youth Volunteer at HariPrabodham [2017- Present]

February 2019 - March 2019